<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Micro posts on jason.re</title><link href="https://jason.re/status/index.xml" rel="self"/><link href="https://jason.re/status/" rel="alternate"/><updated>2022-02-20T21:05:18+01:00</updated><id>https://jason.re/status/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name><email>blog@jason.re</email></author><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><entry><title>It is nice to read that a game studio director seems to care …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20220220210518/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20220220210518/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2022-02-20T21:05:18+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is nice to read that a game studio director seems <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/horizon-forbidden-west-delayed-crunch/">to care about his employees</a> — and it doesn&rsquo;t seem to be empty words either.</p>
<p>I hope that this will be an early turning point in the industry, that other big publishers and developers follow suit and refrain from crunching.</p>
<p>Gamers are a fickle bunch, but they can wait the six months. I don&rsquo;t mind waiting longer for games to be released, but I hate it when publishers announce a release date — while they are fully aware that that they can&rsquo;t keep that date — and then &ldquo;surprisingly&rdquo; move it six to twelve months into the future.</p>
<p>Just give the real release date right from the start and stop bullshitting your customers.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Very interesting thread by Hector Martin, where he goes into …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20220220200531/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20220220200531/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2022-02-20T20:05:31+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Very interesting thread by Hector Martin, where he goes into more detail about the performance of Apple&rsquo;s NVMe drivers, explains how they work and what challenges he is facing under <a href="https://asahilinux.org/">Asahi Linux</a>.</p>
<p>From the looks of it, under macOS, you can either have fast write speeds or data integrity when it comes to NVMe storage:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As it turns out, macOS cheats. On Linux, fsync() will both flush writes to the drive, and ask it to flush its write cache to stable storage.</p>
<p>So, effectively, Apple&rsquo;s drive is faster than all the others without cache flushes, but it is more than 3 times slower than a lowly SATA SSD at flushing its cache. Even if all you wrote is a couple of sectors. You pay a huge flush penalty if you do <em>any</em> writes.</p>
<p>[&hellip;]</p>
<p>macOS doesn&rsquo;t even seem to try to proactively issue syncs; you can write a file on macOS, fsync() it, wait 5 seconds, issue a hard reboot (e.g. via USB-PD command), and the data is gone. That&rsquo;s pretty bad.</p>
<p>[&hellip;]</p>
<p>Not flushing means we cannot guarantee ordering of writes, which means you could end up with actual data corruption in e.g. a database, not just data loss. There&rsquo;s no good way around this other than doing full flushes.</p>
<p>[&hellip;]</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It is a very <a href="https://twitter.com/marcan42/status/1494213855387734019">long thread</a>, but its worth the read.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Well, this is unfortunate. It turns out Apple&#39;s custom NVMe drives are amazingly fast - if you don&#39;t care about data integrity.<br><br>If you do, they drop down to HDD performance. Thread.</p>&mdash; Hector Martin (@marcan42) <a href="https://twitter.com/marcan42/status/1494213855387734019?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 17, 2022</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>Netflix hat seine Drohung wahr gemacht und hat einen ersten …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20211102140000/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20211102140000/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2021-11-02T14:00:00+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Netflix hat seine Drohung wahr gemacht und hat einen ersten <a href="https://about.netflix.com/de/news/let-the-games-begin-a-new-way-to-experience-entertainment-on-mobile" title="Netflix Ankündigung">klitzekleinen Schritt</a> in den Spielemarkt gewagt. Damals, als <a href="https://jason.re/mobile-game-renaissance/">Apple Arcade gelauncht wurde</a>, habe ich mir noch Hoffnungen gemacht das es eventuell doch noch “richtige” Spiele auf Mobilgeräten geben würde. Abseits von “Sternen”, “Talern” und “Schlumpfbeeren”.</p>
<p>Das war leider ein Trugschluss. Bis auf eine Hand voll Entwicklungsstudios die sich richtig Mühe gegeben haben, hat der Großteil der Hersteller einfach die “Schlumpfbeeren” rausgepatcht, ohne aber gross etwas am Spiel zu verändern. Das heißt diese Spiele sind dann sehr schnell frustrierend, weil viel “Grind” erforderlich ist — schliesslich ist die “Buy to Win”-Mechanik nicht mehr vorhanden.</p>
<p>Mal schauen wie es bei Netflix laufen wird. Auf iOS scheint es aus den bekannten Gründen (noch?) nicht verfügbar zu sein. Viel Hoffnung habe ich aber nicht 👾🕹.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Shit, I am feeling really old today. macOS was released 20 …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20210524153000/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20210524153000/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2021-05-24T15:30:00+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shit, I am feeling really old today. <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/03/24/mac-os-x-launch-20th-anniversary/">macOS was released 20 years ago</a>. Of course, it was called &ldquo;Mac OS X&rdquo; back then 😄.</p>
<p>I never worked with MacOS 9 myself, but I rembember driving to Düsseldorf to get one of the first copies of MacOS X Tiger in 2005. Back then I had a PowerPC Mac Mini. I remember feeling excited. After years of using a Linux desktop system, it was great to finally have a well-designed graphical user interface, but at the same, don&rsquo;t miss out on the powerful UNIX tools.</p>
<p>Nowadays Windows has caught up a lot with &ldquo;<a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10">Windows Subsystem for Linux(WSL)</a>&rdquo; and their increased support for Open Source software and services. But Apple has a revival of their with their new ARM hardware — even though macOS Big Sur is not so great 😞.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>YouTube, we need to talk. Seriously. Please get over here …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20210508113000/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20210508113000/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2021-05-08T11:30:00+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>YouTube, we need to talk. Seriously. Please get over here for a second.</p>
<p>First of all, I will never pay you 11,99 € per month. That is way too expensive. It is more than Disney+, and just a tiny bit less than Netflix. So please, for the love of God, stop shoving your fucking annoying promotion screens up my ass! It&rsquo;s never gonna happen, not with that price tag.</p>
<p>Second of all, fuck you. Seriously! You are as fucking annoying as TV in the “good ol' days”. Five or six ads in a 30-minute video, and the ads are playing louder than the original video. What the fuck is wrong with you? I know you do it <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/27/youtube-could-soon-equal-netflix-in-revenue.html">for the numbers</a>, the 6bn ad revenue to finance the exec’s third boat must come from somewhere, right?</p>
<p>We are done, YouTube! Do you hear me? Until you come to your senses and offer the premium subscription for a sane price tag — or tone down the ads — we cannot even be friends anymore. I can watch the few longer videos that are of interest to me in another way — one that does not contain any ads at all.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>This is definitely not the worst idea, Microsoft has ever …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20210415180000/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20210415180000/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2021-04-15T18:00:00+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is definitely <a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-teams-blog/streamline-requests-with-new-approval-features-in-microsoft/ba-p/2259871">not the worst idea</a>, Microsoft has ever had. Especially not if your company is all in on Office365. I still hate Teams, though. The whole concept feels wrong to me. But your mileage may vary.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Z9fdqSxKuJw" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>Back in January, Facebook and Google got caught being very …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20210412114215/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20210412114215/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2021-04-12T11:42:15+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in January, Facebook and Google got caught <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-google-jedi-blue-ad-deal-165604926.html">being very cozy with each other</a>. They both looked very shady, and it seemed to be good ammunition for the antitrust lawsuit <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-antitrust-ftc-48-states-194858668.html">they are</a> currently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-antitrust-lawsuit-texas-attorney-general-204043354.html">facing</a>.</p>
<p>They found out now that <a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/21/04/11/google-bernanke-revealed-in-ad-business-antitrust-lawsuit-error">Google wrote a software</a> called “Bernanke” to gain a major advantage over the competition. No one in their sane mind could think that there <strong>is not</strong> an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_antitrust_law">antitrust problem</a> here. Being a buyer and a seller, at the same time, in the same system, reeks of corruption and illegal activities.</p>
<p>Facebook and Google need to be properly regulated, and with a hard hand, in my opinion. They were unregulated for far too long. It is time to get back some of that competition that they stomped out on their way to success.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>When I received the new company Apple Silicon MacBook Pro, I …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20210406163000/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20210406163000/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2021-04-06T16:30:00+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I received the new company Apple Silicon MacBook Pro, I started to use <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjb1tivoOnvAhVVhP0HHUXcDcUQFjAAegQICBAD&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fedge&amp;usg=AOvVaw00nqzEG85NzCdwPK1TK20-">Microsoft Edge</a> for work instead of my old default: <a href="https://www.google.com/chrome/">Google Chrome</a>. I thought it would be a good idea, as we are making heavy use Office365 Enterprise, but I did not want to miss the features and compatibility the the Chromium engine offers.</p>
<p>So far the transition has been very smooth, but one thing drives me crazy. Whenever you copy and paste a link from Edge, <a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/articles/announcing-a-new-way-to-paste-urls-link-format/m-p/1600094">it tries to be smart</a> and adds a link with the title of the page as link text — instead of the plaintext URL.</p>
<p>So fucking annoying! Thank god you can <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-edge/improved-copy-and-paste-of-urls-in-microsoft-edge-d3bd3956-603a-0033-1fbc-9588a30645b4">change the default behavior</a>.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Ich verstehe beim besten Willen den Hype um Clubhouse nicht. …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20210401200045/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20210401200045/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2021-04-01T20:00:45+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ich verstehe beim besten Willen den Hype um Clubhouse nicht. Ein Dienst, der selbst chinesische Dienstleister nutzt und es nicht erlaubt das man Mitschnitte anfertigt, ist in meinen Augen nutzlos. Gerade wo wir anfangen uns von linearen Inhalten zu lösen, gehen wir zurück auf exklusive, lineare Inhalte?</p>
<p>Ich verstehe natürlich, wieso die Leute von der Idee, die hinter dem Dienst steckt, so angetan sind. Der Appeal von (in Corona Zeiten) rar gewordenen &ldquo;Live Events&rdquo; zieht eine Menge Menschen an, die diese Art von Events vermissen, die danach dürsten. Auch wenn ich selbst nie einer von ihnen war.</p>
<p>Jetzt <a href="https://www.heise.de/news/Discord-startet-Clubhouse-Klon-Spotify-und-LinkedIn-und-Co-sind-dran-6004133.html">versuchen es alle zu kopieren</a>, um noch schnell ein Stück vom Kuchen zu ergattern, bevor das Ende der Pandemie den Hype vermutlich extrem abflachen lässt – vielleicht sogar beendet.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Just tried to search for some Django modules in pip and got …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20201222190000/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20201222190000/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2020-12-22T19:00:00+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just tried to search for some Django modules in <code>pip</code> and got a very nasty surprise.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python">ERROR: <span style="color:#a6e22e">Exception</span>:
Traceback (most recent call last):
  File <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;/usr/local/lib/python3.8/site-packages/pip/_internal/cli/base_command.py&#34;</span>, line <span style="color:#ae81ff">224</span>, <span style="color:#f92672">in</span> _main
    status <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> self<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>run(options, args)
  File <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;/usr/local/lib/python3.8/site-packages/pip/_internal/commands/search.py&#34;</span>, line <span style="color:#ae81ff">62</span>, <span style="color:#f92672">in</span> run
    pypi_hits <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> self<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>search(query, options)
  File <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;/usr/local/lib/python3.8/site-packages/pip/_internal/commands/search.py&#34;</span>, line <span style="color:#ae81ff">82</span>, <span style="color:#f92672">in</span> search
    hits <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> pypi<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>search({<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;name&#39;</span>: query, <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;summary&#39;</span>: query}, <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;or&#39;</span>)
  File <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;/usr/local/lib/python3.8/xmlrpc/client.py&#34;</span>, line <span style="color:#ae81ff">1109</span>, <span style="color:#f92672">in</span> __call__
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">return</span> self<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>__send(self<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>__name, args)
  File <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;/usr/local/lib/python3.8/xmlrpc/client.py&#34;</span>, line <span style="color:#ae81ff">1450</span>, <span style="color:#f92672">in</span> __request
    response <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> self<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>__transport<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>request(
  File <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;/usr/local/lib/python3.8/site-packages/pip/_internal/network/xmlrpc.py&#34;</span>, line <span style="color:#ae81ff">46</span>, <span style="color:#f92672">in</span> request
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">return</span> self<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>parse_response(response<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>raw)
  File <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;/usr/local/lib/python3.8/xmlrpc/client.py&#34;</span>, line <span style="color:#ae81ff">1341</span>, <span style="color:#f92672">in</span> parse_response
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">return</span> u<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>close()
  File <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;/usr/local/lib/python3.8/xmlrpc/client.py&#34;</span>, line <span style="color:#ae81ff">655</span>, <span style="color:#f92672">in</span> close
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">raise</span> Fault(<span style="color:#f92672">**</span>self<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>_stack[<span style="color:#ae81ff">0</span>])
xmlrpc<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>client<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>Fault: <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;</span>Fault <span style="color:#f92672">-</span><span style="color:#ae81ff">32500</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;RuntimeError: PyPI&#39;s XMLRPC API has been temporarily disabled due to unmanageable load and will be deprecated in the near future. See https://status.python.org/ for more information.&#34;</span><span style="color:#f92672">&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div><p><a href="https://status.python.org">Python&rsquo;s status site</a> has more nasty details:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Update</strong> — Dec 15, 20:59 UTC<br>
The XMLRPC Search endpoint is still disabled due to ongoing request volume. As of this update, there has been no reduction in inbound traffic to the endpoint from abusive IPs and we are unable to re-enable the endpoint, as it would immediately cause PyPI service to degrade again. We are working with the abuse contact at the owner of the IPs and trying to make contact with the maintainers of whatever tool is flooding us via other channels.<br>
<strong>Monitoring</strong> — Dec 14, 17:46 UTC<br>
With the temporary disabling of XMLRPC we are hoping that the mass consumer that is causing us trouble will make contact. Due to the huge swath of IPs we were unable to make a more targeted block without risking more severe disruption, and were not able to receive a response from their abuse contact or direct outreach in an actionable time frame.<br>
<strong>Update</strong> — Dec 14, 17:30 UTC<br>
Due to the overwhelming surges of inbound XMLRPC search requests (and growing) we will be temporarily disabling the XMLRPC search endpoint until further notice.<br>
<strong>Identified</strong> — Dec 14, 15:09 UTC<br>
We&rsquo;ve identified that the issue is with excess volume to our XLMRPC search endpoint that powers <code>pip search</code> among other tools. We are working to try to identify patterns and prohibit abusive clients to retain service health.<br>
<strong>Investigating</strong> — Dec 14, 09:41 UTC<br>
PyPI&rsquo;s search backends are experiencing an outage causing the backends to timeout and fail, leading to degradation of service for the web app. Uploads and installs are currently unaffected but logged in actions and search via the web app and API access via XMLRPC are currently experiencing partial outages.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Damn, had to happen one day I guess. Single point of failure, infrastructure provided by volunteers and goodwill. Hope they can resolve this soon.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Everyone and their dog are now offering ARM system in their …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20200614144500/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20200614144500/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2020-06-14T14:45:00+02:00</updated><content type="html">&lt;p>Everyone and their dog are now offering ARM system in their portfolio. &lt;a href="https://siliconangle.com/2020/06/11/amazons-new-c6g-r6g-arm-based-instances-now-available/">Amazon now, too&lt;/a>. I think these are only really useful with certain workload types like AI, ML, these sort of things. Wondering how much demand there really is for these kind of systems, and if they make a profit for Amazon 🤔.&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>Kudos HashiCorp! I have to say, your Consul documentation is …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20200119213455/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20200119213455/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2020-01-19T21:34:55+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kudos <a href="https://hashicorp.com">HashiCorp</a>! I have to say, your Consul <a href="https://learn.hashicorp.com/consul/">documentation</a> is the best documentation I have read in a while.</p>
<p>In just a couple of hours I got all the basics I needed to have my own little Consul data center up and running, including certificates and secure communication between the nodes. <a href="https://saltstack.com/">SaltStack</a> needs to step up their game!</p>
<p>Next stop: <a href="https://learn.hashicorp.com/vault">Vault</a>, using Consul as a backend.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Deutsche Unternehmen tun schwer mit Veränderungen, erst …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20200116215238/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20200116215238/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2020-01-16T21:52:38+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Deutsche Unternehmen tun schwer mit Veränderungen, erst recht wenn es digital werden soll. <a href="https://www.golem.de/news/digitalisierung-aber-das-faxgeraet-muss-bleiben-2001-144953.html">Erlebnisse aus dem &ldquo;Schützengraben&rdquo;</a>.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Die neuen AirPod Pro hielten leider nicht lange 😕. Ich habe …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20200111171236/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20200111171236/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2020-01-11T17:12:36+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Die neuen <a href="https://www.apple.com/de/airpods-pro/https://www.apple.com/de/airpods-pro/">AirPod Pro</a> hielten leider nicht lange 😕. Ich habe auch die <a href="https://www.heise.de/mac-and-i/meldung/AirPods-Pro-Probleme-bei-Ohrerkennung-und-Geraeuschunterdrueckung-4628169.html">bei Heise</a> beschriebenen Probleme. Wenigstens ist das Melden und der Austausch bei Apple relativ problemlos.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Today I learned that, even though the Docker Toolbox is …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20200103135015/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20200103135015/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2020-01-03T13:50:15+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I learned that, even though the Docker Toolbox is <a href="https://docs.docker.com/toolbox/">deprecated</a>, <a href="https://github.com/docker/kitematic">Kitematic</a> itself is still under active development. Good for lazy &ldquo;<a href="https://docs.docker.com/docker-for-mac/">Docker Desktop for Mac</a>&rdquo; users like me 🤗.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>I love iTerm2 and I am using it for a couple of years now. I …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20200103130155/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20200103130155/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2020-01-03T13:01:55+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love iTerm2 and I am using it for a couple of years now. I am using a lot of panes and a few tabs, but only rarely move them to a single window because I was never able to move them back. <a href="http://azaleasays.com/2014/03/05/iterm2-merge-a-pane-back-to-window-or-tab-bar/">Until now</a>! Just hit <code>command + shift + option</code> and drag the body for the terminal window back. That was easy! I hope I can remember it.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Interesting how people turn to “heroes” in times like these. …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20191230090617/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20191230090617/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-12-30T09:06:17+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Interesting how people turn to “heroes” in times like these. It is no coincidence that superhero movies and tv shows are en-vogue, people need symbols that inspire them. But sadly, there are not many “leaders” left that exude confidence or hope or even competence — no matter the field in society: thought leaders, political leaders, good examples or otherwise.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZRCdORJiUgU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>Fort Nowhere finally released their version of Bob Dylan’s …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20191219094520/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20191219094520/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-12-19T09:45:20+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fort Nowhere finally released their version of Bob Dylan&rsquo;s iconic song &ldquo;The Times They are A-Changing&rdquo; that was used in the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vLXYfgpqb8Ahttps://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vLXYfgpqb8A">season three trailer of &ldquo;The Crown&rdquo;</a>. I immediately fell in love with the song and now I can finally listen to it all-day on repeat 😁.</p>



<iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/0hNZyq7s2N1N5fYTIZF3zO"
    width="100%"
    height="200"
    frameborder="0"
    allowtransparency="true"
    allow="encrypted-media">
</iframe>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>One of the worst movies that I have ever seen. Without a …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20191209045413/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20191209045413/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-12-09T04:54:13+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From the first minute the movie feels very “constructed” and very “artificial” to me. As if they discovered the comic book story and then decided they want to build a movie around it – no matter how and if the elements fit together and in total disregard of the continuity they just created with the last movies.</p>
<p>They went to great lengths, in &ldquo;First Class&rdquo; and &ldquo;Days of Future Past&rdquo;, to build an at least somewhat believable storyline, and to create a shred of continuity for the X-Men cinematic universe. Just to demolish all that with this movie.</p>
<p>The film has a great cast, but the actors seem to read their uninspired and very descriptive text from a teleprompter. Overall, they deliver very stiff and &ldquo;wooden&rdquo; performances. Even a good cast cannot save horrible direction and writing.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a shame the X-Men series had such a rapid decline in quality. Unfortunately it is not even worth the 3,99 € rental price. 👎</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s wait and see what Disney does with the TV and cinema reboot, that will undoubtably come in the next couple of years.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Wer haette das gedacht?! Kaum laesst man aus den kuenstlich …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20191202113603/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20191202113603/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-12-02T11:36:03+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wer haette das gedacht?! Kaum laesst man aus den <a href="https://www.golem.de/news/eu-roaming-ohne-preisaufschlag-zwoelfmal-mehr-mobile-datennutzung-1912-145297.html">kuenstlich aufgeblasenen Roaming-Preisen die Luft raus</a>, schon nutzen die Leute mehr Daten! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w4aLThuU008">Nein! Doch! Ohh!</a>.</p>
<p>Was passiert wohl, wenn sie erst herausfinden, dass Leute Bandbreite anstaendig nutzen wenn man sie ihnen zu veruenftigen Preisen zur verfuegung stellt. Haette uns das nur jemand vorher mal gesagt!</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Ich habe meine Liebe für französische Musik wiederentdeckt …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20191126094800/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20191126094800/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-11-26T09:48:00+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ich habe meine Liebe für französische Musik wiederentdeckt 😍.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ST9KMkSgLp4" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Spotify hat sogar eine &ldquo;This is Zaz&rdquo; Playlist von Isabelle Geffroy.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
]]></content></entry><entry><title>For me, Windows really could be an alternative to macOS in a …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20191123153429/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20191123153429/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-11-23T15:34:29+01:00</updated><content type="html">&lt;p>For me, Windows really could be an alternative to macOS in a year or two. WSL2 and Windows Terminal look great. Once their final version was released and the toolset is stable, it could get really interesting, really fast.&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>I am on the fence here. It looks good, but at the same time …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20191122171423/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20191122171423/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-11-22T17:14:23+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am on the fence here. It looks good, but at the same time I am a bit disgusted by the use of a microwave for &ldquo;cooking&rdquo;. But I think I would give it a try! 🤔</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-_gQoJaiMgQ" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>😳 WOW, that is ugliest thing I have seen in a long time. 80s …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20191122130023/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20191122130023/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-11-22T13:00:23+01:00</updated><content type="html">&lt;p>😳 WOW, &lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/cybertruck">that is ugliest thing&lt;/a> I have seen in a long time. 80s Sci-Fi B movies have called, they want their cheap ass prop back! But the cult of Tesla will say it is the greatest thing since sliced bread and buy it anyway!&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>I loved playing Mechwarrior in the 90s, and also dabbled in …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20191121173859/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20191121173859/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-11-21T17:38:59+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I loved playing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MechWarrior">Mechwarrior</a> in the 90s, and also dabbled in the Tabletop game for a while. The graphics really look great and I cannot wait to play <a href="https://mw5mercs.com/">Mechwarrior 5: Mercenaries</a>. I hope it is as good as it looks.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/E5FWZYuyeDY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>I thought about getting “Ghost Recon: Breakpoint”, but after …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20191001220222/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20191001220222/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-10-01T22:02:22+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought about getting &ldquo;<a href="https://ghost-recon.ubisoft.com/game/en-us/breakpoint">Ghost Recon: Breakpoint</a>&rdquo;, but after reading this <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GhostRecon/comments/dbav23/ghost_recon_breakpoint_first_look_monetisation/">Reddit</a> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/ghost-recon-breakpoint-s-microtransactions-explained-1838678464">Kotaku</a> posts, and watching the video below, I am seriously reconsidering. I guess I will wait it out and buy some kind of &ldquo;Ultimate Edition&rdquo; on sale in a year or so. The game will have matured, be patched and most of the content will be released by then.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tGFBC55_MVg" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I will wait and see what other reviewers write about the game, especially <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK9_x1DImhU-eolIay5rb2Q">ACG</a> and the <a href="https://www.gamespodcast.de/">Games Podcast</a>. And then make a final decision.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Es ist viel zu warm. Eine weitere tropische Nacht die mich …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190827035657/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190827035657/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-08-27T03:56:57+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Es ist viel zu warm. Eine weitere tropische Nacht die mich schlecht schlafen lässt. Es ist schon eine Weile her, dass ich mir „aktiv“ einen Sternenhimmel angesehen, oder einfach nur einen Sonnenaufgang genossen habe.</p>

<figure class='figure image-figure'>
    <img class="image" src='https://rmbr.eu/file/dstore/19/8/27D01C63-34CA-4C28-BC08-68D641FDC2F6.jpeg'>
    
</figure>


<p>Es ist so still und friedlich. Für einen Moment scheint die Zeit still zu stehen und die Welt um mich herum hört auf zu existieren.</p>
<p>Absolute, friedliche Stille. Mein kleiner „Zen“ Moment. Davon bräuchte ich mehr.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>This really looks amazing. We will see what this means for …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190808225615/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190808225615/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-08-08T22:56:15+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/E1OunoCyuhY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>This really looks amazing. We will see what this means for other &ldquo;CI/CD As A Service&rdquo; companies and their solutions. Many in my Twitter timeline already think that this could be the decline for many of these services.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">______________<br>/`          RIP       ` \<br>|                             |<br>| CI as a Service |<br>|                             |<br>|    2011-2019    |<br>|                             |</p>&mdash; rtyler.ua (@agentdero) <a href="https://twitter.com/agentdero/status/1159513243053780993?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2019</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>There will be a Trine 4, it will be released on October 8 …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190808224758/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190808224758/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-08-08T22:47:58+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Yg9w4jRHX8A" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>There will be a Trine 4, it will be released on October 8 and it looks simply marvelous! I hope the multiplayer mode will be as much fun as in the last games!</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Wenn man das so kurz, prägnant und präzise herunter …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190716111257/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190716111257/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-07-16T11:12:57+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wenn man das so kurz, prägnant und präzise herunter gebrochen bekommt, fragt man sich, wieso sich das &ldquo;Heute Journal&rdquo;, die &ldquo;Tagesthemen&rdquo; oder ähnliche öffentlich-rechtliche Programme nicht damit auseinander setzen? Vielleicht mal mit Hintergrundberichten und kritischen Interviews? Wieso bekomme ich dort stattdessen nur ständig &ldquo;Horse Race&rdquo;, &ldquo;Köpfe&rdquo; und unkritische Fragen?</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cc-elFcs96Y" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Kommen die Journalisten sich nicht blöd vor, wenn zwei Satiriker ihren Job machen? Einen viel besseren sogar, wenn es darum geht Bewegung in die öffentliche Debatte zu bringen?</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>A very good opinion piece in the Washington Post.
Telling …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190716105816/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190716105816/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-07-16T10:58:16+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A very good <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/george-conway-trump-is-a-racist-president/2019/07/15/b13c0bd4-a740-11e9-9214-246e594de5d5_story.html">opinion piece</a> in the Washington Post.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Telling four non-white members of Congress — American citizens all, three natural-born — to “go back” to the “countries” they “originally came from”? That’s racist to the core. It doesn’t matter what these representatives are for or against — and there’s plenty to criticize them for — it’s beyond the bounds of human decency. For anyone, not least a president.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Every Republican politician who is not speaking up is silently approving this behavior. And with their inaction, they are supporting racism and should be ashamed of being a citizen of the United States.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Sorgfältig geliefertes Paket von Amazon Logistics So geht …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190527172256/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190527172256/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-05-27T17:22:56+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[
<figure class='figure image-figure'>
    <img class="image" src='https://rmbr.eu/file/dstore/19/5/IMG_0135-2.jpeg' alt='Sorgfältig geliefertes Paket von Amazon Logistics'>
    <figcaption class="figure-caption image-figure-caption">Sorgfältig geliefertes Paket von Amazon Logistics</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>So geht man nicht mit Elektronik um. Das ist leider der (sehr niedrige) Standard auf dem Amazon Logistics operiert. Ich nutze Amazon nun seit fast 20 Jahren, aber so schlimm war es noch nie. In 99% der Fälle klingelt der AMZN Bote ein Mal, und dann nach 10 Sekunden sofort beim Nachbarn. Und der Fahrer heute war der Erste in diesem Jahr der überaus freundlich war und Deutsch gesprochen hat. Leider übertreibe ich hier nicht 😞.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Dubstep is not only noise, as some people claim it to be 😆.</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190526232026/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190526232026/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-05-26T23:20:26+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/d8s8e8JdGCc" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Dubstep is not only noise, as some people claim it to be 😆.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Magnificent and worthy piece! Rest in Peace, Keith Flint 😢.</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190526231926/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190526231926/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-05-26T23:19:26+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/h7Xz1J5tmGs" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Magnificent and worthy piece! Rest in Peace, Keith Flint 😢.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>I am now working with Linux for more than 20 years, but I …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190526194838/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190526194838/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-05-26T19:48:38+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am now working with Linux for more than 20 years, but I have never, ever encountered the <a href="https://www.tecmint.com/access-linux-server-using-a-jump-host/">ProxyJump</a> or the <a href="https://ma.ttias.be/use-jumphost-ssh-client-configurations/">ProxyCommand</a> SSH client configuration options before. They make life so much easier for some of the environments I have to connect to!</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Freshly cleaned and re-organized office! Finally got the …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190526192326/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190526192326/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-05-26T19:23:26+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[
<figure class='figure image-figure'>
    <img class="image" src='https://rmbr.eu/file/dstore/19/5/IMG_0127.jpeg' alt='Freshly cleaned and re-organized office!'>
    <figcaption class="figure-caption image-figure-caption">Freshly cleaned and re-organized office!</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>Finally got the office organized - it was about time. It only took about 18 months for me to weed out the cable mess and give it a good &ldquo;Spring Cleaning&rdquo;. All that remains is to hide the cables on the left side. I already ordered the cable channels.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Folks, this is why you never, ever pre-order a game. …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190505052117/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190505052117/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-05-05T05:21:17+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Folks, this is why you never, ever pre-order a game. Bethesda destroyed every bit of respect and customer loyalty they had with this. What a shame. Nowadays, it looks like almost every company that made a name for themselves is just a shadow of what they once were.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kjyeCdd-dl8" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>I have the same thought for the last couple of years, but I …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190424153706/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190424153706/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-04-24T15:37:06+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have the same thought for the last couple of years, but I was never able to articulate it in a short and poignant way. In my opinion, <a href="https://overcast.fm/+CdQwKWV0/1:04:00">Marco Arment&rsquo;s comment</a> is exactly on-point. The shift to mobile and mobile design dumbs down interfaces and removes &ldquo;power users&rdquo; from the equation. <strong>Especially</strong> on the Mac!</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Interessant. Apple gibt angeblich “hundreds of millions of …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190415191557/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190415191557/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-04-15T19:15:57+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Interessant. Apple gibt angeblich &ldquo;<a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2019/04/15/apple-arcade-500m-plus-budget-report/">hundreds of millions of dollars</a>&rdquo; aus um ca. 100 Spiele in ihre &ldquo;Apple Arcade&rdquo; Subscription zu bekommen. Insgesamt sollen es über $500 Mio. sein. Die Titel sollen allerdings nicht allzu lange exklusiv an Apples Dienst gebunden sein. Eine Renaissance des Mobile Gaming, fernab von &ldquo;Schlumpfbeeren&rdquo; und Microtransactions? Ein großes Sprungbrett für Indie-Spieleentwickler?</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Muss ich gestehen, ich hätte nicht gedacht das Microsoft das …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190415061403/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190415061403/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-04-15T06:14:03+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Muss ich gestehen, ich hätte nicht gedacht <a href="https://www.heise.de/hintergrund/Die-Datenschutz-GAUs-in-Office-365-4374551.html">das Microsoft das so &ldquo;verkackt&rdquo;</a> – auf Deutsch gesagt. Die sind auf einem so guten Weg mit Windows 10, VS Code usw. Und dann so etwas. Ich hoffe die Behörden in 🇳🇱 und 🇩🇪 nehmen sich der Sache jetzt an und hauen da mal richtig drauf. Gerade die DSGVO so derart mit Füßen zu treten, wo das doch wochenlang so ein heißes Thema war. Und die ist ja jetzt auch nicht erst seit gestern in Kraft.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Mandalorian still image Disney presented “The Mandalorian” …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190415034339/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190415034339/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-04-15T03:43:39+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[
<figure class='figure image-figure'>
    <img class="image" src='https://rmbr.eu/file/dstore/19/4/mandalorian_feature.jpg' alt='Mandalorian still image'>
    <figcaption class="figure-caption image-figure-caption">Mandalorian still image</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>Disney presented &ldquo;<a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/the-mandalorian-exclusive-footage-revealed-at-star-wars-celebration-chicago-panel/">The Mandalorian</a>&rdquo; on the <a href="https://www.starwarscelebration.com/">Star Wars Celebrations</a> this weekend. After a disappointing <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=adzYW5DZoWs">Episode IX teaser trailer</a> and an even worse title, this new series and its premise at least <em>looks</em> interesting. We will see if and when the new Disney+ Streaming channel reaches Germany.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Merkel sagte, sie sei dabei durchaus bereit, harte …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190216221223/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190216221223/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-02-16T22:12:23+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Merkel sagte, sie sei dabei durchaus bereit, harte Positionen gegenüber Russland zu beziehen. Sie zeigte sich besorgt über die Ausnutzung der Möglichkeiten hybrider Kriegsführung durch Russland, aber auch durch jemanden wie Steve Bannon. Die Freitagsproteste deutscher Schüler sind aus Merkels Sicht auch Ergebnis hybrider Kriegsführung. So begrüßenswert die Einmischung der Schülerinnen und Schüler zu dem Thema sei, ist eine solch massive und plötzliche Bewegung nicht anders zu erklären. (<a href="https://www.heise.de/newsticker/meldung/Merkel-auf-Muenchner-Sicherheitskonferenz-Auch-Sicherheit-ist-vernetzt-4311091.html">Heise</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://blog.fefe.de/?ts=a296a17d">Fefe</a> hat recht. Es kann niemals daran liegen, dass sie in der Zukunft ungerne zur Arbeit schwimmen möchten – oder noch ein bisschen länger saubere Luft atmen wollen. Völlig abwegig das Ganze! 🤦‍♂️</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>The prude Americans did it! They successfully removed all …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190201132608/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190201132608/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-02-01T13:26:08+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The prude Americans did it! They <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019/01/31/sex-censorship-killed-internet-fosta-sesta/">successfully removed</a> all the &ldquo;smudge&rdquo; from the Internet! 🎉 Of course, they didn&rsquo;t really clean it up and got rid of all the &ldquo;filth&rdquo;. They just swept it under the rug. Couldn&rsquo;t have any side-effects, could it?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Stories with the word &ldquo;porn&rdquo; in them are important because they&rsquo;re about censorship, sexual health, business trends, sex work, politics, gender and women. They&rsquo;re about people.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Oh well.. 🤷🏻‍♂️</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Well, some companies have just switched from their …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190129235152/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190129235152/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-01-29T23:51:52+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, some companies have just switched from their on-premise Exchange installation to Office365 and OneDrive. Maybe they should have listened to their engineers about the <a href="https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/01/24/office_365_down/">ongoing</a> <a href="https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/01/29/office_365_outage/">problems</a> with Microsoft&rsquo;s cloud offering. I am sure the decision to focus on Azure for SaaS deployments is only because the service quality is top notch, not because some suits met on the golf course and offered a metric shit ton of service credits.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Apple just released their quarterly results for the first …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20190129231114/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20190129231114/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2019-01-29T23:11:14+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple just released their <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2019/01/29/apple-1q-2019-results/">quarterly results</a> for the first fiscal quarter for 2019 (in the real world, that is Q4 2018). The results were as expected after the <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2019/01/02/apple-lowers-q1-2019-revenue-guidance/">warning</a> they issued late last year.</p>
<p>Some interesting tidbits from the telephone conference though. I would put them into the &ldquo;No shit, Sherlock!&rdquo; category:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tim, you think the phones might <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2019/01/29/tim-cook-price-a-factor-declining-sales/">have been a tad too expensive</a>? NO FUCKING WAY!</li>
<li>Customers <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2019/01/29/apple-lower-upgrades-explanation/">hold on to their phones</a> because they are build well and are still &ldquo;good enough&rdquo;. Really? And maybe because new ones are <strong>fucking expensive</strong> , too?</li>
</ul>
<p>So they are now <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2019/01/29/iphone-price-cuts-international-markets/">lowering the prices</a> in some international markets, like China, Brazil and India. Fat chance they will do that in Europe, too. But who knows, they seem desperate.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>It has been a while that a piece of stand-up has caught me …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20180828012214/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20180828012214/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2018-08-28T01:22:14+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a while that a piece of stand-up has caught me so off-guard and took me on a real journey. It was funny, so it left me entertained, but it also left me thoughtful and pensive, and at the end deeply moved. Definitely watch it till the end as it has a build-up and a twist.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/5aE29fiatQ0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>Tom “The Tech Chap” shows off his top 5 of thin &amp; light …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20171123110604/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20171123110604/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-11-23T11:06:04+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/XgcFd3gJn7w" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Tom “The Tech Chap” shows off his top 5 of thin &amp; light Laptops with Intel 8th Gen Quad-Core processor.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>woohoo! Just enabled macOS TouchID for sudo
Huge thanks to …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20171122195025/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20171122195025/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-11-22T19:50:25+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">woohoo! Just enabled macOS TouchID for sudo<br><br>Huge thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/cabel?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@cabel</a> for sharing this awesome &amp; simple tip <a href="https://t.co/yAKWbgjDPM">https://t.co/yAKWbgjDPM</a> <a href="https://t.co/CSzTeIWAFA">pic.twitter.com/CSzTeIWAFA</a></p>&mdash; William Lam (@lamw) <a href="https://twitter.com/lamw/status/933377790409183232?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 22, 2017</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This is one of three reasons I could ever imagine using the fucking macOS touchbar! Otherwise this thing is an utterly useless piece of shit.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>A couple of days ago the Washington Post wrote an article …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20171122104113/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20171122104113/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-11-22T10:41:13+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple of days ago the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/comic-riffs/wp/2017/11/18/how-a-star-wars-video-game-faced-charges-that-it-was-promoting-gambling/">Washington Post</a> wrote an article about EA’s Battlefront 2. It was the first time I read something this thorough and detailed about a game and its mechanics in a general media publication — and not in a gaming blog or podcast.</p>
<p>After some countries in Europe already started investigating several games for loot boxes and gambling, it seems that Hawaii will be the <a href="https://kotaku.com/hawaii-wants-to-fight-the-predatory-behavior-of-loot-1820664617">first state</a> to do so in the US. I hope, that many other states will join them and that this lootbox madness will be phased out of the games rather quickly now.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_akwfRuL4os" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>Paul Miller, talking about his year offline and what he …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20171016212258/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20171016212258/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-10-16T21:22:58+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/trVzyG4zFMU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Paul Miller, talking about his year offline and what he experienced when he “reconnected” with the Internet and Social Media.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>We in the IT industry in general, and me in particular, very …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20170915105037/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20170915105037/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-09-15T10:50:37+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We in the IT industry in general, and me in particular, very much like to complain. A lot. The recent iPhone release, and the expected price increase, helped me quite a bit to deflate my head and return a bit closer to Earth.</p>
<p>I am in a remarkably privileged situation. I am very lucky, very fortunate, to be able to think about spending many people’s monthly net salary on a <em>phone</em> , a <em>technical gadget</em> , without restricting myself, or limiting other expenses in any way.</p>
<p>I am not a fan of any religion, so “Thank God” is out of the question. But I am thankful, very much so indeed.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Just the latest example why the SSL certificate industry is …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20170721134506/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20170721134506/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-07-21T13:45:06+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.hboeck.de/archives/888-How-I-tricked-Symantec-with-a-Fake-Private-Key.html">Just the latest example</a> why the SSL certificate industry is widely regarded as shady and has such a bad reputation. Not the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2017/03/google-takes-symantec-to-the-woodshed-for-mis-issuing-30000-https-certs/">first</a> time <a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2011/03/comodo_group_is.html">either</a> that Symantec or Comodo are in the news because of their sloppy security practises. There are rumours that Symantec and other companies want to sell their SSL businesses as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>Good riddance!</p>
<p>Let’s hope that the <a href="https://letsencrypt.org/2017/06/28/hundred-million-certs.html">awesome</a> <a href="https://letsencrypt.org/2017/06/14/acme-v2-api.html">work</a> of <a href="https://letsencrypt.org">Let’s Encrypt</a> will accelerate the extinction of these shady and insecure Certificate Authorities. I predict that the launch of <a href="https://letsencrypt.org/2017/07/06/wildcard-certificates-coming-jan-2018.html">wildcard certificates</a> will be the last nail to the coffin of the CA business model. And with it, the begginning of the end for these dishonest and untrustworthy practices.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Atom now with built-in GitHub support. Finally, it was about …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20170616045735/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20170616045735/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-06-16T04:57:35+02:00</updated><content type="html">&lt;p>Atom now with &lt;a href="https://github.atom.io/">built-in GitHub support&lt;/a>. Finally, it was about time! Just installed the new version yesterday. Not that the GitPlus plugin was not good, but it feels better if it is directly integrated into the core product.&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>Summary and comparison of all new models and options. I am a …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20170607130601/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20170607130601/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-06-07T13:06:01+02:00</updated><content type="html">&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/11519/apple-updates-mac-laptops-pro-vanilla-air-all-get-new-cpus">Summary and comparison&lt;/a> of all new models and options. I am a bit disappointed by Apple. Now everything is on Kay Lake, the ultra-portable MacBook now supports up to 16 GB of RAM. But a 32 GB option for the MacBook Pro’s is nowhere in sight. I still hope it will be a “silent update” in the fall.&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>Ansible works pretty well with DigitalOcean, and where it is …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20170514193325/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20170514193325/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-05-14T19:33:25+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.ansible.com/">Ansible</a> works pretty well with <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">DigitalOcean</a>, and where it is not, it is mostly the fault of <a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/dopy">dopy</a>, not DigitalOcean’s or Ansible’s. I am using macOS and out of convenience I installed Ansible via <a href="https://brew.sh/">Homebrew</a>. When trying certain actions, for example destroying a Droplet, I got this error message:</p>
<p><code>dopy &gt;= 0.2.3 required for this module</code></p>
<p>This was weird, as I was sure I had installed dopy via pip (and pip via Homebrew). After double-checking and some digging I found the issue to be with the Ansible installation. To fix the issue at hand, one can <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?hl=ru#!topic/ansible-project/gjQM-rArtTg">either</a> add</p>
<p><code>localhost ansible_connection=local ansible_python_interpreter=python</code></p>
<p>to the hosts file, <a href="https://github.com/ansible/ansible-modules-core/issues/360">or</a> run</p>
<p><code>/usr/local/Cellar/ansible/2.3.0.0_2/libexec/bin/pip install dopy==0.3.7a</code>.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Very interesting story from Loran Kloeze, describing how to …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20170512160656/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20170512160656/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-05-12T16:06:56+02:00</updated><content type="html">&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.lorankloeze.nl/2017/05/07/collecting-huge-amounts-of-data-with-whatsapp/">Very interesting story&lt;/a> from Loran Kloeze, describing how to create a database of phone numbers, profile pictures and status information without much difficulty.&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>After seven years (at least, the oldest email I could find …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20170114145845/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20170114145845/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-01-14T14:58:45+01:00</updated><content type="html">&lt;p>After seven years (at least, the oldest email I could find was from 2008) I cancelled my &lt;a href="http://www.sipgate.de">Sipgate&lt;/a> account today. My main reason for getting Sipgate in the first place was the “pdf to fax” feature, which got pretty unreliable over the past 2 years or so. Either the fax arrived completely distorted or it did not arrive at all. As I have not used the Sipgate VoIP landline for the last 3 years, the last reason to keep the account is gone now.&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>My Synology DS1815+ now has 16 GB of memory. Thanks to Mike …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20170106142931/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20170106142931/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2017-01-06T14:29:31+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My <a href="https://www.synology.com/en-global/products/DS1815+">Synology DS1815+</a> now has <a href="https://www.alternate.de/Crucial/SO-DIMM-16GB-DDR3-1600-Mac-Kit-Arbeitsspeicher/html/product/1080357">16 GB</a> of memory. Thanks to <a href="https://miketabor.com/about/">Mike Tabor</a>, who tried it as one of the first and wrote a <a href="https://miketabor.com/how-to-upgrade-synology-ds1815-16gb-ram/">blog post</a> about it.</p>

<figure class='figure image-figure'>
    <img class="image" src='https://rmbr.eu/file/dstore/17/1/Screen-Shot-2017-01-06-at-13.19.00.png'>
    
</figure>


]]></content></entry><entry><title>Version 2.0 der Tagesschau App habe ich gerade geloescht. …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20161215185426/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20161215185426/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2016-12-15T18:54:26+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.tagesschau.de/inland/app-start-101.html">Version 2.0</a> der <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/de/app/tagesschau/id401644893?mt=8">Tagesschau App</a> habe ich gerade geloescht. Die App ist noch unuebersichtlicher geworden, was zu 90% daran liegt das nun das Bewegtbild im Fokus liegt. Wenn man denn mal den Knopf gefunden hat, ist das Schriftbild beschissen gewaehlt, die Schrift zu klein und die Sortierung nur nach “Alle Nachrichten” und “Personalisiert” moeglich. Keine Sortierung mehr nach Themen wie “Wirtschaft”, “Inland”, “Ausland” usw. Auch den Tagesschau24 Live-Feed und die letzte Sendung der Tagesschau gibt es nun nicht mehr direkt auf der ersten Seite. Fast koennen sie einem leidtun. Es ist ja nicht so als haetten sie die <a href="http://www.taz.de/!5083029/">Entscheidung freiwillig getroffen</a>.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Finally finished Mafia 3. Despite all it’s problems and bugs …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20161023192636/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20161023192636/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2016-10-23T19:26:36+02:00</updated><content type="html">&lt;p>Finally finished Mafia 3. Despite all it’s problems and bugs – even on the PS4 – I really liked the story and the voice actors. I will probably buy the DLC’s in a sale though. If you can get the game and it’s DLC packs later for around 20 EUR, I recommend buying it. Might write a detailed review later this month.&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>Google just presented their new phones to the world, and to …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20161004211300/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20161004211300/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2016-10-04T21:13:00+02:00</updated><content type="html">&lt;p>Google just presented their &lt;a href="https://madeby.google.com/phone/">new phones&lt;/a> to the world, and to be honest, I am not impressed at all. But I am very surprised that the price tag now matches the iPhone’s. Not the smartest move.&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>The Oatmeal has yet another comic that speaks right to my …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20161004164334/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20161004164334/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2016-10-04T16:43:34+02:00</updated><content type="html">&lt;p>The Oatmeal has &lt;a href="https://theoatmeal.com/comics/unhappy">yet another comic&lt;/a> that speaks right to my heart. It is my favorite comic. I always wondered about this weird thing called “happiness”.&lt;/p></content></entry><entry><title>Apples gives a maximum of 16 GB of memory for a 27-ich, …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20150528183411/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20150528183411/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2015-05-28T18:34:11+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apples gives a maximum of 16 GB of memory for a 27-ich, mid-2011 iMac. The screenshot below proves them otherwise:</p>

<figure class='figure image-figure'>
    <img class="image" src='https://rmbr.eu/file/dstore/15/5/Screen-Shot-2015-05-28-at-17-26-21.jpg' alt='iMac System Report'>
    <figcaption class="figure-caption image-figure-caption">iMac System Report</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>The iMac works fine with 32 GB of memory. I finally have a little bit of leeway to use <a href="http://www.vmware.com/products/fusion-pro">VMware Fusion</a> properly. Maybe Yosemite will even finally run smoothly now.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>One way to permanently get rid of the Windows Firewall is to …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20150513195500/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20150513195500/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2015-05-13T19:55:00+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One way to permanently get rid of the Windows Firewall is to disable the service in the Services Manager, or set the startup type to “Manual”. Today I learned that it is not enough to disable the “Windows Firewall” service when you are on a Windows 7 or Windows 2008 R2 Server. You also have to disable the “Base Filtering Engine” if you do not want to hit a big red brick wall (also known as “Block mode”).</p>
<p>More on the topic in the <a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/networking/archive/2009/03/24/stopping-the-windows-authenticating-firewall-service-and-the-boot-time-policy.aspx">Technet blog</a> and this <a href="https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc766337(WS.10).aspx">Technet article</a>.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>The English version of Alexander Lehmann’s short film ‘We …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20150104061954/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20150104061954/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2015-01-04T06:19:54+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The English version of Alexander Lehmann’s short film &lsquo;We love surveillance&rsquo; has premiered on the <a href="http://media.ccc.de/browse/congress/2014/31c3_-_6608_-_en_-_saal_1_-_201412301545_-_premiere_we_love_surveillance_-_alexander_lehmann.html">31C3</a>. Seven reasons why we love surveillance, and why you should also love it!</p>
<h1 id="english">English</h1>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UKLMKNP0Qy8" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h1 id="german">German</h1>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qGvZveB1osw" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>Apple recently changed their prices for the Apple iCloud …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20140913133211/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20140913133211/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2014-09-13T13:32:11+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple recently changed their prices for the <a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT5879">Apple iCloud storage</a>. 5 GB are free, as usual. For just 0,99 EUR per month you can upgrade to 20 GB.</p>
<p>The initial free tier with 5 GB is not much when you have to back up two iPhones, some data from your Macs and an iPad. I thought long and hard if I really want to continue to backup my devices to the cloud, or I if I want to build the infrastructure at home and on my own systems to create local backups and securely sync them to my own servers. I decided to go with the online cloud backup for now, but also to start to build my own solution, on my own infrastructure.</p>
<p>Apple makes it really easy to upgrade, and the price is really cheap. I think they want to get as many people as possible to upgrade from the free tier to the next higher (20 GB) tier. If you multiply a Dollar with millions of customers, even this really low price can be profitable I guess.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>A co-worker of mine made me aware of this awesome band, …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20131117215611/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20131117215611/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2013-11-17T21:56:11+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A co-worker of mine made me aware of this awesome band, called &ldquo;<a href="http://www.last.fm/music/Red+Fang">Red Fang</a>&rdquo;. I got immediately hooked and got their albums &ldquo;<a href="http://redfang.bandcamp.com/album/whales-and-leeches-deluxe-version">Whales and Leeches</a>&rdquo;, &ldquo;<a href="http://redfang.bandcamp.com/album/murder-the-mountains-deluxe-edition">Murder the Mountains</a>&rdquo; and &ldquo;<a href="http://redfang.bandcamp.com/album/red-fang">Red Fang</a>&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Especially the song &lsquo;Wires&rsquo; caught my attention. Not sure why, but I think it is the heavy, full and aggressive sound of the bass guitar and guitars that I feel sounds really great.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xuR_GxPYFGU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>When I read news like this, I begin to think that we are not …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20121115023436/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20121115023436/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2012-11-15T02:34:36+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I read news <a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/world/uk-man-amazing-new-robotic-arm-article-1.1198220">like this</a>, I begin to think that we are not so far away from the future depicted in <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kq5KWLqUewc">DeusEx: Human Revolution</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I have been blown away by the robotic hand, I could sit and watch it all day. I feel like the Terminator. […] Prior to this I used prosthetic limbs provided by (England’s National Health Service) which were horrible.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The geek in me almost instantly thinks about <a href="http://www.harrr.org/robotpower/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/LukeHand.jpg">Luke’s mechanical hand</a> or the famous scene in <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aAr8llumKnY">Terminator II</a>. Yes, I might exaggerate a bit. But the <a href="http://bebionic.com">invention</a> of this prosthetic seems to me like a real breakthrough in robotics/bionics and also seems to improve it’s wielders quality of life.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Account erstellt: 29 April 05 23:43 CEST
Letzter Login: 11 …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20090723025456/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20090723025456/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2009-07-23T02:54:56+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Account erstellt: 29 April 05 23:43 CEST<br>
Letzter Login: 11 Juli 09 05:14 CEST<br>
Account-Typ: Account für Wrath of the Lich King<br>
Accountstatus: Eingefroren</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My World of Warcraft account is now “frozen”. Been there, done that: Goodbye Azeroth!</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title>“The Day the Routers Died”. The lyrics can be found here.</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20071031124711/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20071031124711/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2007-10-31T12:47:11+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;The Day the Routers Died&rdquo;. The lyrics can be found <a href="https://www.secret-wg.org/2012/04/10/the-day-the-routers-died/">here</a>.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_y36fG2Oba0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content></entry><entry><title>Wer eine sehr zynische und vor allem satirische Songkritik …</title><link rel="related" href="https://jason.re/status/20060525173023/"/><id>https://jason.re/status/20060525173023/</id><author><name>Jason Friedrich</name></author><updated>2006-05-25T17:30:23+02:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wer eine sehr zynische und vor allem satirische Songkritik lesen möchte, dem sei das Buch <a href="http://www.amazon.de/exec/obidos/ASIN/3896026933/qid=1148566447/sr=8-1/ref=sr_8_xs_ap_i1_xgl/302-2280419-6980819">“I Hate Myself And Want To Die – Die 52 deprimierendsten Songs aller Zeiten”</a> ans Herz gelegt. Tom Reynolds analysiert auf unterhaltsame Weise 52 Songs und lässt selten ein gutes Haar an den Interpreten und Songwritern. Nichts desto trotz hat er die Meisten – wenn nicht sogar alle – dieser Songs gehört und weiss wovon er spricht. Wer allerdings jedes Wort auf die Goldwaage legt, sollte dieses Buch nicht kaufen. An manchen Stellen findet sich schon recht derber schwarzer Humor, mit einer ordentlichen Portion Zynismus. Das Buch ist sehr gut ins Deutsche übersetzt, wer aber trotzdem das englische Original lesen möchte, wird hier <a href="http://www.amazon.de/exec/obidos/ASIN/140130835X/qid=1148566447/sr=8-2/ref=sr_8_xs_ap_i2_xgl/302-2280419-6980819">fündig</a>.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>